Guide to the Bayrd Still Papers MC.44
New York University Archives
- Series I: Subject, Historical Reference, and Personal Files, 1933-1988
  - Subseries B: Historical Reference Files, 1933-1988
    - Blacks in Greenwich Village, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Ronald L., Project on Benjamin F. Butler and the early history of instruction in law at New York University, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Budget figures, comparative, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Buildings, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bun, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Butler, Charles, information on, in Haeger, INVESTMENT FRONTIER, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Cast iron buildings, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Chamber of Commerce Portraits, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Chase Administration, Enrollment figures, 1933-34 through 1951-52, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Chase Administration, Registrar's reports, 1941-42 through 1950-51, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Chemistry, Facilities for Instruction in, mid 1850's-1930, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - City and University - relationship of University to New York City, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Colleges and schools at N.Y.U., history of, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Columbia University, nature of at time of founding of N.Y.U., undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Continuing Education, School of, history of, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Dakin, James - Notes on Arthur Scully, Jr., James Dakin, Architect, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Enrollment figures, scattered; age at entrance, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Ferris, Isaac, background of election as chancellor, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Foreign born in New York City: notes and statistics, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Founders, aims of; Franklin D. Roosevelt reference to; memorial to Legislature, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Founding of NYU, notes on, 1965-1976 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Gallatin, Albert, facsimile of letter to John Delafield, Jan. 10, 1831 on structure of proposed University, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Gallatin Associates BULLETIN, Historical items for, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Greenwich Village, "East Village," 1966 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Greenwich Village Historic District, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Greenwich Village houses; John P. Roome House; Isaacs-Hendricks House, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "Greenwich Village and Washington Square Neighborhood," Talk, Greenwich Village Society for Historic Preservation, May 12, 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225055 8
    - Greenwich Village, Transition 1825-30 to 1925-30, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Heights Campus, first year at: student activities, buildings, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hell's Kitchen Chronicle - Reed and Maren Erskine, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - History of University, reference to, in catalogs and bulletins, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - History, Study of, in planning and early practice of New York University; Jared Sparks Committee of Literary Convention (1831); talk to Park History Honor Society, May 14, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hone, Philip, residence, site of Woolworth Building; reference to "uptown" movement, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - James, Henry, birthplace of; correspondence with Grace Lippman, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Kalb, Milt, interview in WASHINGTON SQUARE NEWS, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Landmarks Preservation Legislation, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Law, early instruction in; dates and notes by William C. Noyes; list of deans, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lecture Series, 1871, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Literary Convention, 1830, notes of B. Still on report of, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Literary Greenwich Village - walking tour, notes for, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Literary Societies, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Longworth Map of New York City, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Mathews, J.M., Recollections, notes on, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Matriculants, 1885-86, course preference, religious preference, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Mini-series on the history of N.Y.U. by Bayrd Still, March 4, 11, and 18, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Morse, Samuel F.B., 1982 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Ninth Ward, Evolution of, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Pedagogy, School of, Origins, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Chase Administration, Manuscripts by Bayrd Still -Revised 1st Draft, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Periodicals, notes from an unfinished project to construct genealogy of student publications 1833 to 1933, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Phelps Lectures, History of; details on lectures by Brooke Hindle, 1979, 1976-1979 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Pintard, John, reference to proposed new university, then being discussed in literary convention, 1830, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225056 6
    - Salmagundi Club, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Seal, use of, on diplomas, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Seminar on History of Cities in American life, notes and bibliography, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Rufus, Quotations from, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - St. Luke's-in-the-Fields, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - St. Marks-in-the-Bowery, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Student attitudes, 1939; later 1960's, remarks of Philip Mayerson, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Student Regulations, 1837, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Tallmadge, James - address at dedication of University Building May 30, 1837; aims of founders, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - University College, 1933-1950, from digests of Deans' Reports (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "Utility" and utilitarianism, concern for, in founding; later references to, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Villagers, interested in history of Greenwich Village, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Violet as symbol, origins of, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Walking Tours and Slide Shows - Greenwich Village, Lower City, and Washington Square Campus, 1976-1982 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Washington Square College, 1933 to 1950, from digests of Deans' Reports, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Washington Square College, publications bearing on background and history of, written by J.B. Munn, T.C. Pollock, faculty committees, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Washington Square Park, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Wolfe, Thomas, 1938-1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Weisman, Winston, "A New View of Skyscraper History", undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Acting Dean, Univ. College, Creation of position of Provost, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Quiertt, Glenn- Quotation on city growth, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Washington Square- Data on, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Campus walking tour, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Kristol, Irving. "It's Not a a Bad Crisis to Live In" NYT magazine Jan. 22, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - New York- General, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Subseries D: Personal Notebooks, 1926-1974
    Subseries D contains Stills personal student notebooks, some early teaching notebooks, and later travel notebooks.
    - Student Notebook, 1926-1939 (Box 66)
    - Academic Notebooks, Grade Books, Air Force Books, Travel Notebooks, correspondence, 1926-1974 (Box 67, Folder 1-10, Box 68, Folder 1-11)
- Series II: Research, Committees, Talks, Reviews, Still's Articles, 1935-1977
  Series II contains materials relating to Still's research, scholarship, and writings.
  - Subseries A: Published Sources, 1942-1977
    Subseries A contains publications by others on urban history.
    - Arensberg, Conrad M., "American Communities", 1955 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225059 0
    - Tisdale, Hope, "The Process of Urbanization", 1942 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Handlin, Oscar, "Modern City as a Field of Historical Study", undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tucker, Louis L., "Some Perils in the Writing of Urban History", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Wohl, R. R., "Urbanism, Urbanity, and the Historian", undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Buder, Stanley, "Broad Approach to American Urban History", undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Lubove, Roy, "Urbanization, Technology, and the Historian", undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Davis, Allen F., "The American Historian vs. the City", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Wade, Richard C., "The Urban Dimension of Western Life, 1790-1830", undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Lampard, Eric, "American Historians and the Study of Urbanism", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Popenoe, David, "Education for Urban Studies", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Webb, W. P., "The American West Perpetual Mirage", 1957 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Zuckerman, Michael, PEACEABLE KINGDOMS, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Cook, Edward M., "Local Leadership and Typology of New England Towns, 1700-1785", 1971 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Konig, David, Letter re urbanism in colonial America, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Lockridge, K. A., A NEW ENGLAND TOWN...DEDHAM, MASS., 1636-1676, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Lockridge, K. A., "Land, Population and the Evolution of New England Society, 1640-1790", 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Lockridge, K. A. and Alan Kreider, "Evolution of Massachusetts Town Government, 1640-1740", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Rutman, Darrett B., WINTHROP'S BOSTON...1630-1649, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Rainbolt, John C., "Absence of Towns in 17th-century Virginia", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Reps, John, Urbanism in Southern Colonies, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Ernst, Joseph A. and H. Roy Merrens, Urban Process in Southern Colonies, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Population of towns in colonial and early national periods, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Suffrage in towns in colonial America, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Bailyn, Bernard, NEW ENGLAND MERCHANTS IN THE 17th CENTURY, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Grant, Charles S., DEMOCRACY IN CONNECTICUT FRONTIER TOWN OF KENT, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Labaree, B. W., PATRIOTS AND PARTISANS: THE MERCHANTS OF NEWBURYPORT, 1764-1815, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Lemon, J. T., Urbanization in 18th Century SW Pennsylvania and Delaware, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Powell, S. C., PURITAN VILLAGE (Sudbury, Mass.), undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Henretta, J. A., Colonial Boston, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Kirker, H. and J., BULLFINCH'S BOSTON, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Main, Jackson T., Revolutionary America, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Maier, Pauline, Popular Uprisings in 18th-century America, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Walsh, Richard, Charleston Mechanics, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Lemisch, Jesse, Merchant Seamen in Revolutionary America, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Wood, Gordon S., Mobs in American Revolution, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Egnal, Marc and Joseph A. Ernst, Economic Interpretation of American Revolution, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Griffiths, Ernest; Carl Bridenbaugh, Government and Politics, Colonial City, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Smith, Page, AS A CITY UPON A HILL, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Warden, Gerard B., BOSTON, 1689-1776, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Warner, S. B., PRIVATE CITY, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Warner, S. B., URBAN WILDERNESS, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Mohl, Raymond, Poverty in New York City, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Pessen, E., City Government, 1825-1850, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Harris, Jonathan, Medicine, N.Y.C., 18th and 19th centuries, undated (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Barth, Gunther, San Francisco and Denver, undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Green, Constance M., WASHINGTON, D.C., I and II, undated (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Nadeau, Remi, LOS ANGELES, undated (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Thernstrom, Stephan, POVERTY AND PROGRESS; THE OTHER BOSTONIANS, 1964, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Wade, Richard C., URBAN FRONTIER, undated (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Wade, Richard C., "An Agenda for Urban History", 1971 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Wade, Richard C., M.A. Program in Urban Archives, undated (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Pred, Allan, "Industrialization.. and...Metropolitan Growth", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Kristol, Irving, Watergate, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Knights, Peter, PLAIN PEOPLE OF BOSTON, 1830-1860, undated (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - Thernstrom, Stephan and Peter R. Knights, MEN IN MOTION, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Callow, A., TWEED RING, undated (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - Callow, A., Readings, undated (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - Pred, Allan, Manufacturing in American Mercantile City, 1800-1840, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - Rischin, Moses, PROMISED CITY, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225060 8
    - Taylor, G. R., Cities and Transportation Revolution, 1964-1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Handlin, Oscar, BOSTON'S IMMIGRANTS; NEWCOMERS, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Nelli, Humbert, Italians in Chicago, 1966-1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - McKelvey, B., Cities and Self-conscious Minorities, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Blumin, S., Social Mobility, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Mandelbaum, Seymour, BOSS TWEED'S NEW YORK, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Siegel, A., CHICAGO'S FAMOUS BUILDINGS, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Mumford, Lewis, "Regions to Live In"; "What Is a City?" (1925), Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Hays, Samuel, "Politics of Reform in Municipal Government in the Progressive Era", 1964 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Davis, Allen, SPEARHEADS FOR REFORM, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - George, Henry, Reaction to New York City, 1868-1890, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Johnstone, Paul H., "Old Ideals vs. New Ideas in Farm Life," 1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Clark, T. D. and A. B. Kirwan, Urbanization in the South, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Vance, Rupert, Metropolitan Dominance in the South, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Skolnik, Richard, "Civic Group Progressivism in New York City", 1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Frey, Ruth, "The City in the American Novel, 1865-1900", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Lubove, Roy, TWENTIETH-CENTURY PITTSBURGH, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Abbott, Carl, "Boom State and Boom City" (Denver), undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - City Planning (Reps, Scott, et al), undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Police, selected cities, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Richardson, James, New York Police, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Larsen, Lawrence H., Street Sanitation, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - McKittrick, Eric, Corruption, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Meuriot, Paul, DES AGGLOMERATIONS URBAINES DANS L'EUROPE CONTEMPORAINE, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Legoyt, M. Alfred, DU PROGRES DES AGGLOMERATIONS URBAINES...(1867), undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Lampard, Eric, Selected Writing, 1955-1974 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Thernstrom, Stephan, "Reflections on the New Urban History", 1971 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Ebner, Michael, "New Urban History", 1973 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Kessner, Thomas, THE GOLDEN DOOR, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - White, Dana, "...American Urban History", 1971 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Briggs, Asa, VICTORIAN CITIES; review of URBAN HISTORY YEARBOOK 1974 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Manuel, Frank, re Cities, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Definitions of City and Urbanization, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Dahl, Robert A., "The City in the Future of Democracy", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Williamson, Jeffrey G., "Antebellum Urbanization in American Northeast", undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Higgs, Robert, "Growth of Cities, Midwest, 1870-1900", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225061 6
    - Feller, Irwin, "Urban Location of U.S. Invention", undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - White, M. and L., INTELLECTUAL VS. THE CITY, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Vandiver, J. S., "Urbanization and Urbanism in U.S.", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Bogue, Donald J., "Urbanism in U.S.," 1955 - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Roebuck, Janet, SHAPING OF URBAN SOCIETY Review, SOUTH ATLANTIC QUARTERLY, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Original Research, 1962-1976
    Subseries B contains research on urban history and includes statistics, travel accounts, maps, and charts.
    - Auto Registration, 1900-1957, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Lees, Andrew, German Cities, Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers New York City, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - New York Jews and Quest for Community, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - East Bridgeport, Conn., Urbanization of, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Urban Universities - Bibliography, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Lure of City - Picture, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Litwack, Leon, NORTH OF SLAVERY (1960), Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Negro in Northern Cities to 1870 - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Negro Population Movement to Cities, 1967-1972 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Apartment Houses Early Reaction to (1870), undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Bond Street, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Pease, Otis, "Urban Reformers in the Progressive Era", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Borchert, John, American Metropolitan Evolution, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Fuller, Buckminster, on Cities, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Turner, Frederick Jackson, References to significance of city (1922) notes taken by Bayrd Still at Huntington Library, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Jacobs, W. R., HISTORICAL WORLD OF FREDERICK JACKSON TURNER, review by Bayrd Still, in NEW-YORK HISTORICAL SOCIETY QUARTERLY, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Urbanism and Westward Movement: notes and articles, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Pomeroy, Earl, Urbanism on Pacific Coast, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Feldman, Egal, Historians and City, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Archdeacon, T. J., NEW YORK CITY, 1664-1710, 1976 AMERICAN HISTORICAL REVIEW, review by Bayrd Still (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - New York Archival Society, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Cemeteries and Urban Land Use, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Maps Showing Urban Places, 1840, 1850, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225062 4
    - Travel Accounts Describing Life in America, 18th and Early 19th centuries, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Travel Accounts Describing New York City, 1830-1850, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Accounts of British Travelers Describing New York City, Library Inventory, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Travel Accounts Describing America, 1828-1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Cities, Description of, in Travel Accounts (Index), undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Foreign Travelers in America, 1810-1935", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Urban Population in Colonial America, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - U.S. in 1870: A Statistical View, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Rural-Urban Pattern of Population: U.S. Census of 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Urban-Rural Population - U.S., 1790-1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Population Growth of Representative Cities and Metropolitan Areas, 1920-1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Thirty Representative Cities: Census of 1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Increase in Number of Large Cities, 1870-1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Urban Proportion in Population on of States and Sections: 1820, 1870, 1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Population of Selected Cities and Metropolitan Areas: 1920, 1940, 1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Thirty Representative Cities - City and Urbanized Area 1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Urbanism by State and Section - 1820, 1870, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Percentage of Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1860, 1870, 1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Manufacturing in American Cities - 1860, 1870, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Rank of Cities by Value of Manufactures 1860, 1910, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Sources of Immigration to U.S. - 1820 to 1950. Peak Years, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Immigration by Country of Last Permanent Residence 1860 to 1900, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Foreign Born in Western States, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Population of 50 Largest Cities, 1900-1960; by Rank, 1940,1960; Area, 1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Population Patterns, Trans-Allegheny West, 1830, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1850, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Nativities of Inhabitants, Selected Cities, 1850, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1860, 1870, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1860, 1870, 1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Foreign Born by Rank in Selected Cities, 1900, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Foreign Born by Rank in Selected Cities, 1910, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Foreign Born by Rank in Selected Cities, 1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Foreign Born in Selected Cities, 1920, 1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Foreign Born By Country of Birth, Selected Cities, 1900, 1910, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Percentage of Foreign Born and Slaves in Total Population, by State, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Statistics on Slaveholding, by States, 1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Black Population in Selected Cities, 1860, 1870, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Black Population, Selected Cities, 1860, 1870, 1900, 1920, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Black Population in Selected Cities, 1920, 1940, 1950, 1960, 1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Trans-Allegheny West, 1830, 1860: Population Patterns, urban/rural, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Trans-Allegheny West, 1830, 1860: Population Increase, Percentage Foreign Born, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - New York City, Population for Selected Years, 1620-1955, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Growth of 30 Representative Cities, Listed by Section, 1640-1950, undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - City Course Charts and Exhibits, Reading Lists, undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Dongan Charter, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Subseries C: Published Sources, 1962-1973
    - Dana, C. W., THE GREAT WEST (1857), undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Merlin, Didier, "Amerique derriere un pare-brise" (America behind a Windshield) travel account, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, NEW YORK, undated (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Vest, Charlene, "Image of the City: Graphic Representation, 1880-1889", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - DeTocqueville, Alexis, re Westward Settlement, undated (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - Trumbull, H., WESTERN EMIGRATION, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Kalaigis, Jim, "Tenderloin Riot in in New York City, August, 1900", 1973 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Power, Tyrone, Journey on Erie Canal, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225063 2
  - Subseries D: NYU Committees, 1956-1971
    Subseries D contains administrative files from Bayrd Still's years as acting dean.
    - All-University Departments, 1956-1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Acting Dean, University College, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Self-Study, Views concerning future of University College, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Report, Acting Dean, (University College), written by Bayrd Still, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Dean's Report (University College), written by Thomas Robinson, June 30, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Report, Acting Dean, (University College), written by Bayrd Still, June 1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Committee to Select Dean of Graduate School, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Committee to Select Executive Dean, December 1961-June 1962, 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 9)